<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Office365 on WRISH</title>
    <link>http://www.wrish.com/tags/office365/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Office365 on WRISH</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 23:47:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.wrish.com/tags/office365/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Powershell get Exchange Online IP addresses (for Firewall rules)</title>
      <link>http://www.wrish.com/post/quickly-get-exchange-online-ips/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 23:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.wrish.com/post/quickly-get-exchange-online-ips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This one-liner will download the Office 365 IP list XML file and extract the IPv4 addresses for EOP and Exchange Online.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assign EMS licenses to all licensed users with dynamic groups</title>
      <link>http://www.wrish.com/post/assign-ems-licenses-with-dynamic-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 11:42:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.wrish.com/post/assign-ems-licenses-with-dynamic-groups/</guid>
      <description>Azure conditional access provides flexible control over access to Office 365 resources and services based on location/user group membership/device etc. If you set up conditional access rules, any user who doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an Azure AD Premium license will not be affected by them - access is permitted by default!
How to work around this without manually assigning licenses to every user or using a dodgy script? Azure AD has a capability called Dynamic Groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assign EMS licenses to all licensed users</title>
      <link>http://www.wrish.com/post/assign-ems-licenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 11:42:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.wrish.com/post/assign-ems-licenses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Azure conditional access provides amazingly flexible control over access to Office 365 resources and services based on location/user group membership/device etc. Leveraging it to block access generally requires EMS (Enterprise Mobility + Security) licenses for all users. This short script will assign EMS licenses to all users in your tenant who are licensed but do not have EMS yet.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office 365 - Convert between Immutable ID and AD Object </title>
      <link>http://www.wrish.com/post/convert-between-immutableid-and-ad-object/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 20:53:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.wrish.com/post/convert-between-immutableid-and-ad-object/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two quick scripts to convert between ImmutableIDs and AD Objects with pipeline capability.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>