<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azuread on WRISH</title>
    <link>http://www.wrish.com/tags/azuread/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azuread on WRISH</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 11:42:35 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.wrish.com/tags/azuread/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assign EMS licenses to all licensed users with dynamic groups</title>
      <link>http://www.wrish.com/post/assign-ems-licenses-with-dynamic-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 11:42:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.wrish.com/post/assign-ems-licenses-with-dynamic-groups/</guid>
      <description>Azure conditional access provides flexible control over access to Office 365 resources and services based on location/user group membership/device etc. If you set up conditional access rules, any user who doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an Azure AD Premium license will not be affected by them - access is permitted by default!
How to work around this without manually assigning licenses to every user or using a dodgy script? Azure AD has a capability called Dynamic Groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office 365 - Convert between Immutable ID and AD Object </title>
      <link>http://www.wrish.com/post/convert-between-immutableid-and-ad-object/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 20:53:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.wrish.com/post/convert-between-immutableid-and-ad-object/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two quick scripts to convert between ImmutableIDs and AD Objects with pipeline capability.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure AD Connect - Cannot Retrieve Single Sign On Status</title>
      <link>http://www.wrish.com/post/cannot-retrieve-single-sign-on-status-aadconnect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 20:53:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.wrish.com/post/cannot-retrieve-single-sign-on-status-aadconnect/</guid>
      <description>If you landed here, then you are very unlucky. You downloaded AADConnect version 1.1.370.0 with it&amp;rsquo;s known issue. You don&amp;rsquo;t have port 9090 open externally, so you don&amp;rsquo;t get an undocumented error Cannot retrieve single sign on status. Learn more.
But do not fear. Just go and download the latest version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to verify an Azure AD domain</title>
      <link>http://www.wrish.com/post/unable-to-verify-azure-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 11:42:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.wrish.com/post/unable-to-verify-azure-domain/</guid>
      <description>After you&amp;rsquo;ve added a domain to Azure AD (or Office 365) using powershell, while connected to your ADFS like this:
New-MsolDomain -Name domaintest.wrish.com -Authentication Federated  When you add your verification record and try to verify the domain from the GUI you might get an error like this:
You can&amp;rsquo;t verify your domain using the GUI when you create the Domain using powershell, instead you have to confirm the domain using powershell while entering all Federation options.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>